William Mayger

Address: 47 Chalfont Drive,

Gillingham,

Kent,

ME8 9DW

Mobile Number: 07514494820

Email: will.mayger@theweblancer.com

Github: https://github.com/WillMayger

Website: http://theweblancer.co.uk/

Creative CV (Please Visit): http://willmayger.uk/

Linked In: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/will-mayger-6aa5659a

Skills:

Node.jsJavascript

- React.js

- Express.js

- Less

- CSS - SCSS

- SCSS - HTML

- Jquery

- Git

- SVN

ES6

- Chai

- Angular

- Heroku

- AWS

- MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Web Design

- Graphics Design

- Python

- Django

- Photoshop

Bootstrap

- Responsive websites

- Java

- C#

- ASP.NET

MySQL

Cloud Foundry

- Flask

Profile:

I have been working in web development professionally for the last 3 - 4 years. I originally started because I had a deep fascination with being able to create things with a computer. The first bit of code I wrote was for making a macronutrients calculator for fitness when I was 16 years old in C#. Ever since I have been completely obsessed with development. The only part of my motives that have changed is that I found I love web development the most, especially with Node.js, which I discovered after I started my apprenticeship in London with the company, Atos.

Web development is a deep passion for me, even after I finish a day of work I will happily go home and work on personal projects that usually involve using new technologies to keep me learning and pushing myself forward, not to mention keeping up with the current standards. It fills my need of being challenged, creative.

I also like to work until the task at hand is completed, at both work, and personal things. Due to this I have a tendency to annoy my girlfriend when working on projects as It takes a while to pull me away from the screen!

As a side note, I am actively learning french with a native speaker, my girlfriend (ma petite ami!). I often go over to France to visit her family who do not speak a word of english. This suits me well though as I like the challenge and the learning I get from speaking with them and seeing different parts of the world.

Objective:

I am looking to keep learning and pushing myself in the world of web development. The main technologies i want to be improving on and utilizing are Node.js / JS, HTML, CSS. I also have a preference to improving on my knowledge of React.JS and making use of it.

I want a role that will keep pushing me and challenging me to learn and improve on new skills as well as build on my existing ones. I would like to and I am prepared to take on plenty of responsibilities as In my current position we have a lot of responsibilities, builds, tickets and deployments to do with little time to do it so I am used to working under pressure.

Career summary:

01/07/2014 - 10/07/2015 - Apprentice Software and Web Developer at Canopy Cloud (ATOS) - PaaS Team

01/07/2015 - 01/03/2016 - Web Developer and Web Designer at Atos / Canopy Cloud (ATOS) - Research, Innovation and Incubation Team

01/03/2016 - 01/07/2016- Web Developer / Web Designer / Engineer at Atos Engineering

01/08/2016 - Current Date - Front End Web Developer at Gforces

01/01/2016 - Current Date - Private Web Designer and Developer in free time as http://theweblancer.co.uk

Education:

- GCSE: English C
- GCSE: Maths C
- GCSE: I.C.T C
- GCSE: Biology C
- GCSE: Chemistry C
- GCSE: Physics C
- GCSE: Citizenship Studies C
- GCSE: Work skills (BTEC) C
- GCSE: Sport (BTEC) C

- AS-LEVEL: Photography A
- AS-LEVEL: Certificate in financial studies A
- AS-LEVEL: Art D
- A-LEVEL: Photography A*
- A-LEVEL: Diploma in financial studies A
- A-LEVEL: Forensic science Pass
- City and Guilds Software and Web Development level 3

Career History:

In my a levels, my main subject was Photography where we also worked on graphics design. This was heavily based on complex Photoshop graphics and image editing. This is what originally led me to think about websites.

During my A Levels, at home, in my own time I looked to the internet to start learning about development using C# to build a fitness application. After I had completed this, I moved onto learning Java / Android to create an android application for the fitness application I had made with C#.

I applied and successfully got an Apprenticeship at QA and then a Apprenticeship Job at Atos to go with the training. In the Apprenticeship we learnt about C#, HTML, CSS and ASP.NET which I passed and now have a City and guilds Software and Web Development Qualification. During my time at Atos, however, from day one I started learning about, and putting to use, JS, Node.Js, CSS, HTML, Jquery and Git. I made many internal applications that helped different departments handle certain things such as an application to help the finance department deal with invoices so there was no room for error, which meant lots of testing. During this time we used many different technologies because we chose the best for each individual task that needed to be done. (most listed above)

This year in Atos we moved into a closed environment with a team of 1 Senior, 1 Mid, and 2 Juniors where we utilized Node.JS, Express.JS, and Cloud Foundry as the main tech stack to develop a GUI website for Cloud foundry users. We were making use of the Agile methodology Extreme Programming with Pair Programming and TDD. This continued for another year before we finished and then I took the next step in my career.

I Joined Gforces Web Management where almost everything is mostly focused on pixel perfect responsive websites that match designs to the pixel. We make tools in Node.js with various frameworks such as mithril.js to help us speed up the process of making and deploying websites. A couple of examples of sites I have done here are: http://www.gcmotors.co.uk/, http://www.hwm.co.uk/.

I started making personal, and private projects / websites for me and others about halfway through my apprenticeship when I felt that I had really started to get a grasp of all the basics. Since then I have been implementing more and more complex systems as well as technologies to keep learning. Some of which are listed above with the icons!

My latest one would be this very C.V, which has been created in Node.Js with React.JS.

A few others:

- http://theweblancer.co.uk (Old and needs updating)
- http://maygerfitness.co.uk
- I am also working on a Budgeting App using Express.js, MongoDB, Oauth2, and Node.js for the Rest API. React.Js and Node.Js for the view layer.

Personal details:

Key I.T. Skills: Node.is, Javascript, Jquery, React.is, Express.is, ES6, Backbone.is, Chai, Angular

1, CSS, Less, SCSS, HTML, Mithril.js, gulp, Web Design, Web Development, Photoshop, Responsive websites, Programming, Python, Django, C#, Java,

MySQL, TDD, Graphics Design, DNS, Heroku, Cloud, Problem Solving.

Other: Vue.js, Cloud Foundry, Heroku, AWS, Extreme Programming, social media.

Interests: Coding, Node.js, React.js, Web Development, Web Design, Fitness, Nutrition,

Films, Socializing, Graphic Design, Photography, French Language, Traveling,

Experimenting, Learning New things, Problem Solving, Challenges.

References are available on request:

Adam Jackson - Director: Research, Innovation and Incubation at Canopy Cloud

- Email: adam@adamjackson.org.uk
- Email: adam.jackson@canopy-cloud.com (Company email)

Romain Barissat - Technology and Innovation leader

- Email: romain@barissat.com
- Email: romain.barissat@atos.net (Company email)

Georgi Barzev - Canopy Cloud Engineering

- Email: glbarzev@yahoo.com
- Email: georgi.barzev@canopy-cloud.com (Company email)
- Email: georgi.barzev@atos.net (Company email)

Robbie Avni - Trainee Firefighter at London Fire Brigade

(Used to be at Canopy Cloud)

- Email: robster113@gmail.com